<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "User_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>

<chapter id="ittms-Introduction_to_the_Media_Server">
	<title>Introduction to the &THIS.PLATFORM; Media Server</title>
	<section
		id="ittms-Overview-Media_Servers">
		<title>
			Introduction
		</title>

		<para>
			In the modern VoIP world providers are offering highly customized services that combines media such as audio/video or IM. These services require dedicated and customized media processing capabilities. To achieve this the VoIP network separates the media processing functions into dedicated node which is responsible for media processing only, while all the intelligence is executed by the separate call controller.  The node processing media streams is called as Media Server.
		</para>
		<para>
At the same time there are lots of media streams flows in legacy systems. It means that media handling node must be able to bridge the gap between traditional legacy systems and modern VoIP networks. This node typically called as Media gateway but normally media gateway acts as media server too.
		</para>
	</section>

<section id="ittms-What_is_Mobicents_Media_Server">
		<title>What is &THIS.PLATFORM; Media Server</title>
		<para>
The &THIS.PLATFORM; Media Server is open source implementation of the VoIP network element responsible for media handling. The &THIS.PLATFORM; media server supports IP and TDM interfaces and thus can act as media server and as media gateway. &THIS.PLATFORM; Media server provides support for both distributed and centralized services including circuit switch voice/video, announcements, tones, etc.
		</para>
		<para>
		The &THIS.PLATFORM; Media Server is provided with telco standard MGCP interface. The &THIS.PLATFORM; Media server can operate in pair with &THIS.PLATFORM; Jain SLEE application server. However the fully standard MGCP interface allows to use &THIS.PLATFORM; Media Server in pair with another call controller if so desired. &THIS.PLATFORM; Media server is equipped with implementation of the media control API compliant to JSR-309 which allows to use Media server with &THIS.PLATFORM; SIP Servlet Container.
		</para>
		<para>
The &THIS.PLATFORM; Media Server includes embedded signaling gateway function which supports complete set of TDM and IP signaling protocols. Media server supports TDM access variants like ETSI ISUP, PRI. Media server supports signaling backhaul over IP with M3UA and SUA options.
		</para>

		<para>
The &THIS.PLATFORM; Media Server is implemented using JBoss Microcontainer kernel which allows to archive maximum flexibility. It gives the ability to adopt media server for task specific and/or extend the functions of the media server by installing additional media processing components.
		</para>
	
	</section>	
	

</chapter>
